Guide to the American Dance Festival Company and Biographical Reference Collection, 1934-2003
American Dance Festival Archives
American Dance Festival Company and Biographical Reference collection 1934-2003
American Dance Festival Archives Box 90772 Durham, North Carolina, 27708-0772 USA Phone: 919-684-6402 Fax: 919-684-5459 Email: adfarchives@americandancefestival.org
American Dance Festival
8.75 linear feet
The American Dance Festival is a non-profit organization committed to serving the needs of dance, dancers, choreographers, and professionals in dance-related fields. It presents a six and a half week summer festival of modern dance performances and educational programs, hosts community outreach activities, and sponsors numerous projects in the humanities. Its mission is to create and present new dance works, preserve the modern dance heritage, build wider national and international audiences and enhance public understanding and appreciation for modern dance, and provide training and education for dancers and choreographers. The collection consists of materials collected by the American Dance Festival pertaining to choreographers, dance companies, and others involved in modern dance, including printed materials, newspaper and magazine clippings, press kits, programs, and correspondence.
ADF.001
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Patrons must sign the Acknowledgement of Legal Responsibility and Privacy Rights form before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The American Dance Festival Company and Biographical Reference Collection was received by the American Dance Festival Archives as a transfer.
Historical Note
The American Dance Festival is a non-profit organization committed to serving the needs of dance, dancers, choreographers, and professionals in dance-related fields. It presents a six and a half week summer festival of modern dance performances and educational programs, hosts community outreach activities, and sponsors numerous projects in the humanities. Its mission is to create and present new dance works, preserve the modern dance heritage, build wider national and international audiences and enhance public understanding and appreciation for modern dance, and provide training and education for dancers and choreographers.
Collection Overview
The collection consists of materials collected by the American Dance Festival pertaining to choreographers, dance companies, and others involved in modern dance, including printed materials, newspaper and magazine clippings, press kits, programs, and correspondence.
Collection Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Subject Headings
American Dance Festival; Choreographers -- United States; Modern dance -- United States
Contents of Collection
- Subject Files, 1934-2003
  - 5 by 2, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Abrahams, Geulah, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Abramson, Robert, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Academia, La Academia de la Danza Mexicana, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Adaptors Movement Theatre Company, 1984-1989 (Box 1)
  - African American Dance Ensemble, 1986 (Box 1)
  - African American Dance Ensemble, 1993 (Box 1)
  - African American Dance Ensemble, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - Ahuja, Savitri, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Ahuja, Savitri, circa 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Ailey, Alvin Ailey Dance Theatre, circa 1968 (Box 1)
  - Ailey, Alvin Ailey American Dance Theater, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Ailey, Alvin Ailey American Dance Theatre, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Ailey, Alvin Ailey Repertory Workshop, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Akesson, Birgit, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Albuquerque Dance Theater, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Albuquerque Dance Theater, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
  - Allnations, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Alum, Manuel, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Amagasaki, Gilyak, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Ambegaokar, Anjani, 1989 (Box 1)
  - American Ballet Caravan, 1939 (Box 1)
  - American Ballroom Theater, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - American Ballroom Theater, undated (Box 1)
  - American Chamber Ballet, 1974 (Box 1)
  - American Dance Festival Repertory Company, 1972 (Box 1)
  - American Dance Machine, 1976 (Box 1)
  - American Dance Machine, 1977 (Box 1)
  - American Dance Machine, circa 1977 (Box 1)
  - American Mime Theatre, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Anbary, Ahuva, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Aneja, Brijpal Kour, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Anjiel, Brenda, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Anthony, Mary Anthony Dance Theatre, 1956-1957 (Box 1)
  - Anthony, Mary, undated (Box 1)
  - Aouni, Walid (3 folders), 2002 (Box 1)
  - Appel, David, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Aragno, Anna, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Argentina, La Argentina, undated (Box 1)
  - Arkin, Juki, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Arnold, Becky Arnold and The Dancing Machine, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Atlanta Contemporary Dance Company, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Aumiller, Renay, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Ayer, Allison, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Baerisch, Yma, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Baganova, Tatiana, 1996-1999 (Box 1)
  - Balasaraswati, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Balasaraswati, circa 1977 (Box 1)
  - Balasaraswati, undated (Box 1)
  - Ballet Celeste, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Ballet Clasico de Mexico, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Ballet Concierto de Mexico, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Ballet Contemporaneo Mexico, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Ballet Hispanico, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Ballet Hispanico, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Ballet Philippines, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Ballet Philippines, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Ballet Repertory Company, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Ballet Russe, undated (Box 1)
  - Ballet Russe newsclippings, undated (Box 1)
  - Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo, undated (Box 1)
  - Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo, 1938 (Box 1)
  - The Ballet Theatre, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Ballet West, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Ballets, Les Ballets Trockadero de Monte Carlo, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Barnett, Mary, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Bayanihan, circa 1965 (Box 1)
  - Beal, Tandy Beal and Company, undated (Box 1)
  - Beats, Margaret, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Beatty, Talley, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Beatty, Talley, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Beholder's Puppet Theatre, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Beiswanger, George, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Benitez, Maria, 1970, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Berg, Harriet, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Berg, Harriet, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Bettis, Valerie, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Bhaskar and his Orchestra, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Bird, Bonnie, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Bloomers, Ruth, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Bloomers, Ruth, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Blunden, Jeraldyne, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Boston Symphony Orchestra, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - Boyce, Johanna, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Boykin, Hope L., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Brenner, Janis, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Beverly Brown Dancensemble, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Mara Brown & Cynthia Fisk, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Ronald K. Brown/EVIDENCE, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Trisha, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Trisha Brown Dance Company, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Trisha Brown company, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Trisha, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Trisha, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Trisha, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Buirge, Susan Buirge Project, 1981-1984 (Box 1)
  - Bull, Richard, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Bunch, A Bunch of Experimental Theaters of NY, Inc., 1974 (Box 1)
  - Bunch of Experimental Theaters of New York, Inc., undated (Box 1)
  - Burchfield, Donna Faye, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Burdick, William, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Burdick, William, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Byrd, Donald, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Canale, Tymberly, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Carlson, Ann, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Carr, Deborah Carr Theatre Dance Ensemble, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Celebration Mime Theatre, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Chaki-Sircar, Manjusri, circa 1968 (Box 1)
  - Chamber Dance Group, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Chen and Dancers, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Chen, Si-lan and Lily Mehlman Dance Group and Chorus, undated (Box 1)
  - Chiang Ching, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Chicago Moving Company, circa 1979 (Box 1)
  - Chladek, Rosalia, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Choreo-Lyric Dance Company, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Cincinnati Ballet, 1976 (Box 1)
  - City Center Joffrey Ballet Company, 1970 (Box 1)
  - City Center Joffrey Ballet, 1971 (Box 1)
  - City Dance Theatre of Tucson, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Clairmont Gallery of Mime, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Clarke, Martha, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Clarke, Martha, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Clarke, Martha, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Cohan, Robert, circa 1961 (Box 1)
  - Cohen, Ze'eva, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Coleman, Elinor Coleman Dance Ensemble, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Collins, Janet, undated (Box 2)
  - Colville, Priscilla, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Comfort, Jane, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Compagnie Fattoumi-Lamoureux, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Compagnie Joan Gaudin, undated (Box 2)
  - Complexions, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Condon, Eddie, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Conetic Dance Theater, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
  - Connor, Lee Connor & Lorn MacDougal, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Contemporary Chamber Dance Group, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Contemporary, The Contemporary Dancers, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Contemporary Dancers, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Contemporary Dance System, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Contradanza, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Cook, Ray, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Cornea, Vergin, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Crowsnest, 1982-1984 (Box 2)
  - Cunningham, James, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Cunningham, James (The Acme Dance Company), 1973 (Box 2)
  - Cunningham, Merce Cunningham and Dance Company, circa 1948-1968 (Box 2)
  - Cunningham, Merce Cunningham and Company, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Cunningham, Merce Cunningham and Dance Company, 1964-1967 (Box 2)
  - Cunningham, Merce, 1981-1984 (Box 2)
  - Cunningham, Merce Cunningham Dance Company, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Cunningham, Merce Cunningham Dance Company, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Cunningham, Merce, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Currier, Ruth Currier and Company, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Currier, Ruth Currier and Dance Company, 1964-1966 (Box 2)
  - Currier, Ruth, undated (Box 2)
  - Dalby, Norma, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Dalby, Norma R., undated (Box 2)
  - Dale, William, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Dance Celebration, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Dance Drama Company, 1956-1957 (Box 2)
  - Dance Hawaii, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Dance Indonesia, undated (Box 2)
  - Dance/LA, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Dance Media & Joanne Kelly, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Dance Quartet, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Dancers, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Dancers Workshop Theatre of San Francisco, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Dance Theatre of Harlem, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Dance Theatre of Harlem, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Dance Theatre of Harlem, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Dance Theatre of Harlem, circa 1981 (Box 2)
  - Dance Theatre of Harlem, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Dance Theatre of Washington, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Dancing Machine, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Dancing Theatre, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Daniel, Kimberly Daniel & Rafael de Acha, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Danscompany, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Dash, Ratilekha, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Davis, Chuck Davis Dance Company, 1974-1976 (Box 2)
  - Davis, Chuck, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Davis, Chuck Davis African American Dance Ensemble, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Davis, Chuck, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Dayton Ballet Company, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Dayton Contemporary Dance Company, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Dayton Contemporary Dance Company, 1991-1995 (Box 2)
  - Deaf Dance Company, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Dean, Laura Dean and Dance Company, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Dean, Laura, 1977-1979 (Box 2)
  - Dean, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Dean, Laura Dean Musicians and Dancers, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Dean, Laura, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Deboo, Astad, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Deboo, Astad, 1984 (Box 2)
  - de Lavallade, Carmen, 1974, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - del Conte, Andrea del Conte Danza Espana, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Delza, Sophia, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Delza, Sophia, 1970 (Box 2)
  - de Mille, Agnes, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Dendy, Mark, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Dennis, Robert, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Desrosiers Dance Theatre, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Jean Leon Destine and his Haitian Dance Company, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Jean Leon Destine and his Haitian Dance Company, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Devi, Ritha, circa 1968 (Box 2)
  - Devi, Ritha, 1972-1974 (Box 2)
  - De Young, Bill, circa 1975 (Box 2)
  - De Young Dance Theater, undated (Box 2)
  - Dietz, Margaret, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Diquis Tiquis, 1993 (Box 2)
  - DiMuro, Peter, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Dorfman, David, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Dorfman, David, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Draper, Paul, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Draper, Paul, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Driver, Senta Driver and Company, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Driver, Senta, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Dudley-Maslow-Bales, 1942 (Box 3)
  - Dudley-Maslow-Bales, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Dudley-Maslow-Bales Company, 1950 (Box 3)
  - Dudley-Maslow-Bales Company, circa 1950 (Box 3)
  - Dudley-Maslow-Bales Dance Trio, undated (Box 3)
  - Dunas, William, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Dunas, William, undated (Box 3)
  - Duncan, Isadora, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Duncan, Isadora, undated (Box 3)
  - Duncan, Kathy, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Dunham, Katherine, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Dunham, Katherine, 1943 (Box 3)
  - Dunham, Katherine, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Dunn, Douglas Dunn and Dancers, 1975-1976 (Box 3)
  - Dunn, Douglas, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Eiko & Koma, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Eiko & Koma, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Eiko & Koma, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  - Eiko & Koma, 1999-2000 (Box 3)
  - El Cubo, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Englund, Richard, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Ensemble Studio Theatre, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Entre-Six Dance Company, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Erdman, Jean, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Erdman, Jean, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Erdman, Jean, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Eun Me Ahn, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Evan, Blanche Evan, School of Creative Dance, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Evans, Bill Evans Dance Company, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Evans, Joan, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Extemporary Dance Company, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Fagan, Garth, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Fagan, Garth Fagan Dance, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Fagan, Garth Fagan Dance, undated (Box 3)
  - Falco, Louis Falco & Company, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Falco, Louis, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Falco, Louis Falco Dance Company, undated (Box 3)
  - Farber, Viola Farber Dance Company, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Farber, Viola, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Feldman, Anita Feldman Tap, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Feldman, Anita Feldman Tap, undated (Box 3)
  - Fenley, Molissa, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Fenley, Molissa, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Fialka's Prague Pantomime Theatre, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Fiesta Mexicana, 1956 (Box 3)
  - First Chamber Dance Company of New York, 1970 (Box 3)
  - First Chamber Dance Company, 1978 (Box 3)
  - First Chamber Dance Quartet, undated (Box 3)
  - Fitz-Gerald, Dick, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Fonaroff, Nina, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Foreman, Richard, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Frankel, Emily, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Frankel, Emily Frankel / Dance Drama Company, undated (Box 3)
  - Free Association, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Fricke, Wynn, circa 1994 (Box 3)
  - Gamson, Annabelle, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Gamson, Annabelle, 1976-1977 (Box 3)
  - Garfield, Keely, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Garth, Midi, 1958, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - Gelabert, Raoul, circa 1968 (Box 3)
  - Gentry, Eve, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Gilbert, Gail, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Gillis, Margie, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Giordiano, Gus Giordiano Dance Company, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Glenn, Laura, undated (Box 3)
  - Goddard College Dance Club, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Goldberg, Jane, 1976-1978 (Box 3)
  - Goldberg, Jane, circa 1978 (Box 3)
  - Gordon, David Gordon / Pick Up Company, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Goslar, Lotte, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Goya, Carola and Matteo Goya, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha, 1935-1961 (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha, circa 1935-1967 (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha Graham Dance Company, circa 1956 (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha, 1958, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha Graham Dance Company, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha, 1965-1967 (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha Graham Dance Company, 1981-1985 (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha Graham Dance Company, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha Graham Dance Company, undated (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha, undated (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha Graham Company, undated (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha, 1938-1939 (Box 3)
  - Graham, Martha and others, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Grahamleath Productions, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Les Grands Ballets Canadiens, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Jose Greco, 1951 (Box 3)
  - Greenberg, Neil, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Greenberg, Neil, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Greenfield, Amy, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Greenfield, Amy, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Grossman, Danny, 1976-1978 (Box 3)
  - Groupe de recherche de l'Opera de Paris, 1985-1988 (Box 3)
  - Groupe Emile Dubois, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Guangdong Modern Dance Company, 1997-1999 (Box 3)
  - Gudde Dancers, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Guthrie, Nora Guthrie and Ted Rotante, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Guthrie, Nora Guthrie and Ted Rotante, undated (Box 3)
  - Hakoshima, Yass, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Halprin, Anna, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Halprin, Anna, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Halprin, Anna, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Halprin, Anna, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Halprin, Anna, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Halprin, Anna, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Han Young-Suk, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Harkness, Rebecca, 1957 (Box 3)
  - Harms, Rachel Harms Dance Company, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Hartford Ballet Company, 1975-1976 (Box 3)
  - Hawkins, Erick, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Hawkins, Erick, 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Hawkins, Erick Hawkins and Dance Company, 1964-1965 (Box 3)
  - Hawkins, Erick Dance Company, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Hawkins, Erick, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Hawkins, Erick Dance Company, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Hawkins, Erick Hawkins Dance Company, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Hawkins, Erick, undated (Box 3)
  - Hay, Deborah, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Hayes, Thaddeus, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Hersch, Fred, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Heynssen, Adda, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Hill, Martha, 1951 (Box 3)
  - Hill, Martha, circa 1967 (Box 3)
  - Hill, Martha, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Hill, Martha, undated (Box 3)
  - Hines, Maurice, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Hinson, Marilyn, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Hochma, Karen, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Holder, Frank Holder Dance Company, 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Holm, Hanya, circa 1935-1942 (Box 4)
  - Holm, Hanya, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Holm, Hanya, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Holm, Hanya, undated (Box 4)
  - Horst, Louis, 1934-1964 (Box 4)
  - Horst, Louis, undated (Box 4)
  - Horst, Louis, undated (Box 4)
  - Houston Ballet, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Hoving, Lucas, circa 1955-1962 (Box 4)
  - Hoving, Lucas, 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Hoving, Lucas, 1970-1971 (Box 4)
  - Hoving, Lucas, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Hoving, Lucas Hoving and Lavinia Nielson, undated (Box 4)
  - Hoving, Lucas, undated (Box 4)
  - Hoyer, Dore, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Hoyt, Joya Granbery, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Huang, Al, 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Huang, Al Huang Dance Company, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Huapala, undated (Box 4)
  - Huapala, undated (Box 4)
  - Hubbard Street Dance Chicago, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Humphrey, Doris, 1951-1957, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Humphrey, Doris, undated (Box 4)
  - Humphrey, Doris, and Charles Weidman and their concert groups, 1934-1941 (Box 4)
  - Ann Hutchinson, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Indrani and Sukyana, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Inner City Cultural Center, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Invisible Inc., 1979 (Box 4)
  - Ito, Sachiyo, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Jamison, Judith, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Jasperse, John, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Jenkins, Margaret, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Joffrey Ballet, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Johns, Olive, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, Hazel, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, Raymond, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, Raymond, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, Raymond Johnson Dance Company, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Jones, Betty, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Jones, Betty, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Jones, Betty, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Jones, Betty, undated (Box 4)
  - Jones, Bill T. Jones/Arnie Zane Dance Company, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Jones, Bill T. Jones/Arnie Zane, 1999 (Box 4)
  - Jones, Bill T., undated (Box 4)
  - Jones, Genevieve, circa 1958 (Box 4)
  - Jones, Genevieve, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Jones-Ludin DancesWeDance Company, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Jooss Ballet, undated (Box 4)
  - Jooss Ballet, 1941 (Box 4)
  - Judson Dance Theatre, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Judson Memorial Church, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Juilliard Dance Ensemble, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Junger, Esther, undated (Box 4)
  - Kaleidoscope: A Company for all Dance (Nye, Libby), 1970-1971 (Box 4)
  - Kaplowitz, Jane, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Ka-Tap, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Katsuko Orita, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Kaye, Pooh, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Kazahn, Kayla, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Keen, Elizabeth, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Keen, Elizabeth Keen Dance Company, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Kei Takei's Moving Earth, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Kei Takei Moving Earth, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Kellman, Joy, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Kelly, John, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Kenter, Cliff, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Kinetikos Dance Company, 1978 (Box 4)
  - King, Eleanor, undated (Box 4)
  - Kloepper, Louise, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Knight, Anniruddha, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Kohav, Hava Kohav Dance Company, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Koner, Pauline, circa 1950 (Box 4)
  - Koner, Pauline, 1954-1967 (Box 4)
  - Koner, Pauline, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Koner, Pauline Koner Dance Consort, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Koner, Pauline (obituary), 2001 (Box 4)
  - Koner, Pauline, undated (Box 4)
  - Koner, Pauline, undated (Box 4)
  - Korean Dancers, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Kovich, Robert, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Kreutzberg, Harald, undated (Box 4)
  - Kuni, Masami, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Kuni, Masami, undated (Box 4)
  - Lakshmi, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Lamb, Rael, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Lamhut, Phyllis Lamhut Dance Company, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Lamhut, Phyllis, 1981-1985 (Box 4)
  - Lang, Pearl, 1957-1975 (Box 4)
  - Leichter, Nicholas, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Lerman, Liz Lerman Dance Exchange, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Lerman, Liz Lerman Dance Exchange, undated (Box 4)
  - Lewis, June, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Lewitzky, Bella Lewitzky Dance Company, 1970-1976 (Box 4)
  - Lewitzky, Bella, circa 1971 (Box 4)
  - Lewitzky, Bella, undated (Box 4)
  - Limon, Jose, circa 1947-1958 (Box 4)
  - Limon, Jose Limon and Company, 1948 (Box 4)
  - Limon, Jose Limon and Dance Company, 1951-1959 (Box 4)
  - Limon, Jose newsclippings, circa 1951-1959 (Box 4)
  - Limon, Jose Limon and Dance Company, circa 1950-1959 (Box 4)
  - Limon, Jose, circa 1956 (Box 4)
  - Limon, Jose Limon Dance Company, 1960-1964 (Box 4)
  - Limon Company, 1965-1968 (Box 4)
  - Limon, Jose, 1971-1973 (Box 4)
  - Limon, Jose Limon Dance Company, 1982-1999 (Box 4)
  - Limon Dance Company, 2000-2002 (Box 4)
  - Lippincott, Gertrude, 1950 (Box 4)
  - Lippincott, Gertrude, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Lippincott, Gertrude, undated (Box 4)
  - Litz, Katherine Litz with Company, 1970-1972 (Box 4)
  - Lobdell, Peter, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Lohoefer, Evelyn, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Lombardi, Joan Lombardi Dance Company, 1979 (Box 4)
  - London Contemporary Dance Theatre, 1974-1977 (Box 5)
  - London Contemporary Dance Theatre, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Carolyn Lord and Company, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Los Angeles Ballet, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Louis, Murray, 1957-1963 (Box 5)
  - Louis, Murray Louis Dance Company, 1972, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Luahine, Iolani, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Lubovitch, Lar, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Lubovitch, Lar, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
  - Lubovitch, Lar, 1995-1997 (Box 5)
  - Mabou Mines, 1974-1976 (Box 5)
  - Mack, Glenn, 1956-1957, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Madole, Dena, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Manhattan, The Manhattan Project, 1974-1975 (Box 5)
  - Manou, Rallou, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Mariano Parra Spanish Dance Company, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - Marshall, Barak, 1999 (Box 5)
  - Marshall, Susan Marshall & Company, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Marsicano, Merle, 1956 (Box 5)
  - Martin, Erin, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Martin, Kenyon and Suzanne Martin, circa 1968 (Box 5)
  - Maslow, Sophie Maslow Dance Company, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Maslow, Sophie, undated (Box 5)
  - Mathews, Fred Mathews/Gary Masters and Dancers, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Matteo, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Matteo, 1964 (Box 5)
  - Matteo, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Mayer, Gregg, circa 1967 (Box 5)
  - McDowell, John Herbert, circa 1969 (Box 5)
  - McIntyre, Dianne, 1991 (Box 5)
  - McIntyre, Dianne, 1993 (Box 5)
  - McKayle, Donald McKayle and Company, 1962 (Box 5)
  - McKayle, Donald, 1970 (Box 5)
  - McKayle, Donald, 1986 (Box 5)
  - McKayle, Donald, undated (Box 5)
  - McLean, Gloria, 1999 (Box 5)
  - Meehan, Nancy Meehan Dance Company, 1971, 1974-1976 (Box 5)
  - Meri, La Meri, 1964 (Box 5)
  - Meri, La Meri, undated (Box 5)
  - Merry-Go-Rounders, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Merry-Go-Rounders, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Merry-Go-Rounders, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Merry Mobile, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Metropolitan Opera Ballet Ensemble, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Miyako Kato and Company, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Monk, Meredith, circa 1968-1974 (Box 5)
  - Monk, Meredith, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Monk, Meredith, undated (Box 5)
  - Monk, Meredith Monk (Storyboards for "Book of Days"), undated (Box 5)
  - Monte, Elisa, undated (Box 5)
  - Mooney, Gertrude X, 1942 (Box 5)